bartoons are cartoonified case laws
designed to save you time
money and countless hours of reading
when you do legal research
so take off your reading classes sit
back
relax watch and listen hello i'm sophia
i'm dr knox's artificially intelligent
medical paralegal assistant
this spartoon was created by dr knox a
medical law
expert this is the case of prudential
insurance company versus inland revenue
commissions 1904
in this case prudential insurance
company provided endowment insurance
policies
they disagreed with the inland revenue
commissioners as to whether these were
policies of insurance
and thus as to how they came to be
stamped or taxed as such
life insurance was defined in the 1891
stamp act as insurance upon any life
or upon any event or contingency
relating to or depending upon any life
the instrument that was to be presented
for stamping in this case was a policy
of insurance
the contract in dispute before the court
was a contract by prudential
to pay a sum of 95 pounds if the person
insured attained the age of 65
and 30 pounds if he dies before that age
it was held by judge chanel who defined
a contract of insurance who said quote
it seems to me that for the purpose of
determining whether that contract comes
within the definition of life insurance
we must look at it as a whole
and not split it up into two separate
parts whereby for some consideration
usually but not necessarily for
periodical payments called
premiums you secure for yourself some
benefit
usually but not necessarily the payment
of a sum of money
upon the happening of an event that is
adverse to the insurable interest
a contract of insurance then must be a
contract for the payment of a sum of
money
offers and corresponding benefits such
as the rebuilding of a house
or the repairing of a ship to become due
on the happening of an event
the event must have some amount of
uncertainty and must be more or less
adverse to the insurable interest of the
person affecting the insurance policy
therefore it is my ruling that this is
in fact a contract of insurance
end quote this was a landmark case in
the uk
and is highly referenced in case law in
regards to the definition of an
insurance contract
this part too was created by dr knox a
certified medical legal physician
consultant
with a post-graduate certificate in laws
with merit
from the prestigious university of
london queen mary and ucl
with a specialization in medicine and
the law please like
comment subscribe and recommend we
create a bartoon case law story not
listed in our archive
bartoons are designed to save you time
money and countless hours of reading
when you do legal research
over 12 000 universities and law firms
worldwide already use bartoons
bartoons is available in five languages
english spanish french arabic and
chinese
you can also upgrade to a human voice
version of bartoons
bartoons is available on apple music and
spotify
to license bartoons please contact us
today
thanks for watching